statelinetack.com 2008-12-17

# Horse Tack, Horse & Equine Supplies - State Line Tack.com

|   
  
|  |   
---  
  
* * *  
  
* * *  

|  **Privacy Information**  
---  
**State Line Tack**  
  
State Line Tack seeks to be the most trusted, caring, complete and exciting source for all your pet's needs throughout its life. As you do business with us, we take great care in safeguarding your personal information and in complying with all applicable Federal, Provincial, and state privacy laws, as well as our own internal standards and best practices. We want you to know that we value your privacy and are committed to responsible handling of your personal information (such as your name, physical address, e-mail address, and phone number), and we want you to know how we handle your information. 

This Privacy Policy ("Policy") describes the information, privacy and security practices for our Site. We understand and respect your privacy. We provide notice of our information handling practices; give choices about how your personal information will be used; give the opportunity to update or change your personal information; use information security safeguards; limit the sharing of your personal information; commit to complying with applicable privacy requirements; and provide ways for you to contact us about privacy concerns. 

When you participate in any of the activities described in this Policy and provide us with your personal information, you consent to how we collect, use and handle your information as explained in this Policy. Here we tell you what we do and do not do with the personal information you provide to us as you visit our Site and stores; purchase our products and/or services; participate in our programs; and request a catalog.   
  
---  
Collection, Use and Disclosure of Personal Information  
General Information About Our Site and the Internet  
Choices Regarding How Personal Information is Used and Accessing Your Personal Information  
Security of Personal Information  
Secure Online Shopping  
Children  
Questions or Concerns  
Changes/Updates to This Policy  

**COLLECTION, USE AND DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
We may collect personal information when you: shop or take advantage of our products and/or services; establish or update an account with us; enter a contest or sweepstake; participate in a survey; request a catalog; purchase and/or send an e-gift certificate; provide us with comments or suggestions; call our contact center; or subscribe to our newsletters and other programs. We may use your personal information to better assist you when you visit or call us again and to send you special offers for products and services that may be of interest to you. We do this by print advertising, including regular mail and catalogs, by e-mail, by telephone, and with general marketing communications for product or service-specific information. 

Unless you "opt-out" through opportunities available to you through our various communication vehicles, we may send you emails, catalogs or other promotional material. You may also "opt-out" of future State Line Tack Communications by following the instructions provided in this Policy under Choices Regarding How Personal Information is Used and Accessing Your Personal Information. 

**When visiting our Site** , if you register for an online account or for any online offers, we may ask you to provide personal information and to select a password of your own choice to help keep personal information secure. We may use your registration information to help make your online shopping experience and orders quicker and easier, by pre-filling certain parts of your shopping information. 

**When you make online purchases** , we will collect your name, physical address, phone number, e-mail address and billing/shipping information, as well as credit card information. This information enables us to deliver products that you have ordered; fulfill your requests; contact you or the recipient(s) of your purchase in the event of order or delivery difficulties; verify or respond to your inquiries; and deliver services and information about our products or Site to you. If you make a purchase through our Site, the personal information you provide (for example, name, physical address, and e-mail address) will be added to our customer database. Our customer database may be used to send future State Line Tack Communications to you unless you specifically opt-out. Note: Online purchases require use of an e-mail address to process the order. 

**We may share your personal information with carefully selected third-party service providers in order to provide services to you** , such as to fulfill orders (U.S. Postal Service, Canada Post, or other delivery companies we or you select); process payments; send State Line Tack Communications; monitor Site activity; conduct surveys; maintain our customer database; send mail and e-mail; and administer drawings, contests, and rebates. We will share your personal information with our carefully selected third-party services providers on a confidential basis. These service providers are prohibited from using your personal information for any purpose other than providing State Line Tack services. 

**We may combine the personal information you provide to us** (on our Site, at our stores, through our catalogs and programs) with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our marketing partners and others. We use the combined information to enhance and personalize your experience with us; improve the accuracy of our customer database (such as the U.S. Post Office to verify accuracy of addresses); increase our understanding of our customers; identify potential customers; and send State Line Tack Marketing Communications. 

**We may be required to disclose your personal information for legal reasons** , such as in response to a valid court order, subpoena, government investigation, or as otherwise required by law. We also reserve the right to report to law enforcement agencies any activities that we, in good faith, believe to be unlawful. We may release certain personal information when we believe that such release is reasonably necessary to protect the rights, property, and safety of others and State Line Tack. We may also release personal information in the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event. We will require such parties to treat your personal information in accordance with our Policy and to use and disclose your personal information solely for the purposes for which it was collected. 

return to top   
  
**GENERAL INFORMATION ABOUT OUR SITE AND THE INTERNET**  
Our Site uses Web technologies to gather navigational information about our Site and its technical efficiencies and services, such as time to connect to our Site and download pages. This information allows us to see which areas of our Site are most visited and helps improve our understanding of our customers' Site experiences. This practice also helps us improve the quality of online shopping experiences by recognizing and delivering more of the features, services and products our visitors prefer. In the process of gathering navigational information, non-personally identifiable information may be collected, such as domain type, Web browser version, service provider, and IP address, which will provide information about a visitor's use of our Site, like the time of a visitor's last visit to a Site page. 

Our Site uses "cookie" technology. A "cookie" is a small data file that a Website may send to your Web browser and store on your hard drive. Our Site uses cookies to simulate a continuous connection-cookies let us "remember" information about your preferences and session and allow you to move within areas of our Site without reintroducing yourself. No personally identifiable information is stored in these cookies. 

You may choose to set your Web browser to not accept cookies. If your cookies are disabled, you can still view our site and make a purchase. 

We may carefully select third-party advertising companies to collect information by using cookies when you visit our Site. These select companies help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our Site. We respect your right to choose whether to be included in the services that these third parties provide. For more details about your choices for no longer having information from these third-party cookies used by these companies or provided to us, please see Choices Regarding How Personal Information is Used and Accessing Your Personal Information below. 

For your information, we have carefully selected Omniture, a company that will assist us in better understanding your use of our Site. Omniture will place cookies on your computer to collect information on our behalf that will educate us on such things as search engine referral, how you navigate around our Site, responses to e-mail, unique visitor identification, and product browsing and purchasing information. Omniture is contractually prohibited from using our data for any other purposes. Omniture is required to maintain all information collected and its analysis in confidence. As a visitor to our Site, you have the option to deactivate the ability of Omniture to analyze your browsing and purchasing behavior on our Site. To learn how, please go to www.omniture.com/privacy/207. 

Our Site server may automatically collect the address of the Website that you came from before visiting our Site, which Web browser you used to view our Site, and any search terms you have entered on our Site. Our Site may also use other technologies to track pages of our Site viewed by visitors, commonly referred to as "tracer tags". This non-identifiable "click-stream" data helps us understand how visitors use our Site. "Click-stream" is the sequence of clicks or pages requested as a visitor explores a Website. 

As a convenience to you, State Line Tack provides links from its Site to third-party Websites. Inclusion of these links does not imply State Line Tack's endorsement of other companies, their Websites, or their products and services. This Policy does not apply to other Websites that may be accessible through our Site, including third-party sites that display the State Line Tack trademarks or otherwise promote State Line Tack's products and services. We encourage you to read the privacy policies of those other sites and third parties to learn how they collect and use information about you. 

return to top   
  
**CHOICES REGARDING HOW PERSONAL INFORMATION IS USED AND ACCESSING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
If we are currently using your personal information to send you State Line Tack Marketing Communications and you want to change your options, you can "opt-out" of receiving our State Line Tack Communications at any time using the following directions. You may also use these directions to change your personal information and to ask us to stop providing your personally-identifiable information to our carefully selected third-party service providers. 

To "opt-out" of receiving State Line Tack Communications, do one of the following:

1\. If you've created an account on our Site, you can access and change your personal profile information and preferences after logging into your account.

2\. Send an e-mail request to: [ customerservice@StateLineTack.com](mailto:customerservice@statelinetack.com)

3\. Call: Toll-free: 1-800-228-9208  
Monday – Friday 8:00 am – 10:00pm EST

4\. Mail your request to:  
State Line Tack  
Attn: Customer Service  
1 Maplewood Drive  
Hazleton, PA 18202 

If you send us an e-mail or letter, please be sure to include your full name, address, phone number and e-mail address and indicate specifically what type of State Line Tack Communications you wish to stop receiving along with the specific e-mail address to be removed from the mailing list. This will ensure we identify you correctly in our systems so that we may accurately process your "opt-out" request. 

State Line Tack will take the appropriate steps to implement your request to "opt-out". Please note that due to production and mailing timelines, it may take up to ten (10) business days for e-mails and up to six (6) weeks for direct mail and catalog to make the requested change. Until that change takes effect, you may still receive State Line Tack Communications from us, and we apologize for any inconvenience. 

Also, please note that you may still receive business-related communications such as order confirmations, product recall information, or other administrative communications. You cannot "opt-out" of these business-related communications which are necessary to fulfill services. 

return to top   
  
**SECURITY OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
State Line Tack strives to maintain internal controls and procedures to ensure that the personal information you share with us is handled in a safe, secure and responsible manner. Whether you are shopping online or through our catalogs, we have security measures in place to help protect against loss, unauthorized access, and alteration of the information in our control. We will only disclose such information to employees and authorized service providers who require such information for the purposes described in this Policy. 

State Line Tack's databases are protected by physical, technical, and procedural measures that restrict information access to authorized persons in accordance with this Policy. Although no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed 100% secure, and we cannot ensure against any loss, misuse, unauthorized disclosure, alteration, or destruction of data, we take reasonable precautions to prevent such unfortunate occurrences. Our information systems are maintained behind a firewall to isolate them from access by other networks connected to the Internet, and access to personally-identifiable information is granted only to associates who need the information to perform a specific job. 

return to top   
  
**SECURE ONLINE SHOPPING**  
Because your credit card security is a high priority, we have taken numerous steps to ensure your payment information is processed confidentially, accurately, and securely. Our Site uses encryption technology, such as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), to protect your credit card information during data transport. SSL encrypts ordering information such as your name, physical address, and credit card number. 

To provide you with an increased level of security online, when you register for an online account, you may also select a password to access your personal information. State Line Tack will not ask you for your password in an unsolicited communication. 

return to top   
  
**CHILDREN**  
The safety of children is very important to us. Consequently, State Line Tack does not knowingly or intentionally collect information from persons under 13 years of age without parental consent. If you are under 13 and wish to purchase items from our Site or wish to provide personal information, ask a parent or guardian for assistance. State Line Tack cannot prohibit minors from visiting our Site and must rely on parents and guardians to decide which materials are appropriate for children under 13. 

return to top   
  
**QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS**  
To report any known or suspected privacy or security breaches, or to submit privacy-related questions or complaints, please contact us in one of the following ways and we will respond within five (5) business days of receipt of your inquiry. 

**1\. E-mail:** [customerservice@statelinetack.com](mailto:customerservice@statelinetack.com)

**2\. Regular Mail:**

State Line Tack, Inc.  
Attn: Customer Service  
1 Maplewood Drive  
Hazleton, PA 18202 

**3\. Phone:**

Toll-free: 1-800-228-92088  
Monday – Friday 8:00 am – 10:00pm EST 

Please be sure to include your full name, address, phone number, and e-mail address (if applicable), and specifically describe your concern so that it may be appropriately addressed. 

return to top   
  
**CHANGES/UPDATES TO THIS POLICY**  
Because our Site and stores will continue to implement new technologies and improve the products and services we provide, this Policy is subject to change. If there are significant changes or additions to this Policy, we will identify those changes below and/or in other communicative formats to keep you informed of any new information and procedures that may change the way we collect, use, or handle your personal information. If we change our information handling practices or this Policy in such a way that your personal information may be used or shared in a different manner, we will give you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your information used or shared in that new way. 

To help you track significant changes to our Policy, a history of those changes will be notes here, beginning with changes published after June 21, 2007, our last revision date. 

Related Articles...  
Website Conditions of Use   
Website Legal Notices 

return to top   
  
---  
**Check out what fellow equestrians are shopping for on StateLineTack.com...**  
Halters,  Spurs,  Boots,  Bell Boots,  Half Chaps,  Saddles,  Shipping Boots,  Chaps,  Gloves,  Helmet,  Clippers,  Saddle Pads,  Cooler,  Fly Sheet,  Socks  
**_QUICK HELP_** |  **_OTHER SITES_** |  **_SERVICES_** |     
Customer Service |  [Fish Supplies](http://www.fish.com/?srccode=SLTFSH01) |  About statelinetack.com |   Subscribe To Emails  
Order Status & Tracking |  [Ferret Supplies](http://www.ferret.com/?srccode=SLTFER01) |  [Incentive Programs](http://www.incentiveprograms.com/) |  Return Policy  
Shipping & Delivery |  [ Dog Supplies](http://www.dog.com/?intid=SLTDOG01&srccode=SLTDOG01) |  [Pet Adoption](http://www.1-800-save-a-pet.com/) |   Privacy Policy  
Store Location |  [Bird Supplies](http://www.bird.com/?srccode=SLTBRD01) |  Career Opportunities |   Terms & Conditions  
  |  [Pet Supplies](http://www.petsupplies.com/) |  Affiliate Program |   Browse Our Sitemap |
